Helping great companies to build epic apps & websites



Hi, I'm Fernando Guevara. An UX/UI
Designer currently bringing to life simple
and elegant experiences at Acklen Avenue.

For the last 6 years i have been building awesome software products and services hand-in-hand with developers and multifunctional teams across different industries.

My approach is based on human centered design and Lean / Agile methodologies. Learning from users first, identify and validate hypotheses that work and test ideas as soon as possible.

My goal is to create things people want to use and they will actually buy.

Experience

UX/UI Designer

Acklen Avenue Aug 2015 - Present

• Conducting user research and testing • Gathering and evaluating user needs, in collaboration with product managers and clients. • Understanding business requirements and any technical limitations. • Developing wireframes and task flows, UI mockups and prototypes based on user needs . • Collaborating with other designers and Developers to create intuitive, user-friendly software.

Quality Assurance Engineer

Acklen Avenue

Jun 2015 – Aug 2015

• Reviewing quality specifications and technical design documents to provide timely and meaningful feedback. • Creating detailed, comprehensive and well-structured test plans and test cases. • Estimating, prioritizing, planning and coordinating quality testing activities.

HTML & CSS Administrator

Laureate Int. Universities

Apr 2014 – Jun 2015

- Translate and maintain company's visual style guidelines.Executing all visual design stages from concept to final
- hand-off to engineering. Conceptualizing original website design ideas that bring simplicity and user friendliness to complex roadblocks.

Web & Mobile designer

Freelance

Apr 2013 - Feb 2014

 Design conversion-oriented websites for different companies.
 Create digital marketing materials.
 Design user-friendly interfaces for mobile applications
 Enhance client's brand through digital solutions understanding market needs.

Skills & knowledge

Research & strategy

Agile	Usability test	Information Architecture	
Google Analytics Content Strategy			
SEO	A/B testing		

Design

Sketch App	Adobe CC	Prototyping
Wireframing	Branding	Principle
IOS interface des	ign Materia	al design

Code

HTML	CSS	BEM	SASS
Git/terminal	JQuery	Resposive Design	
Javascript			

Other skills i've develop

Learner	Passion for the web		User is always right
Humilty	Team work	Make	people smile :)

Education

UNITEC

2008 - 2012

Bachelor of Arts - BA, Graphic Design.

Languages

English

Spanish